

# **FABIAN ALCANTARA**

**UI & UX DESIGNER** 

1.786.245.3864

hello@fabuloso.me

I am a highly driven, multi-disciplined designer who brings his "A" game in originality, energy, and razor-sharp focus to each project. I have over 8 years of experience in user experience design, creating effortless experiences for higher education and small business clients. My eye for detail and a keen interest in pushing the boundaries in design ensure that I am able to be a natural leader in any creative team.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance Designer

January 2007 - Present

#### Notable Highlights:

Realigned an ecommerce solution to increase sales by improving the user experience. The changes included a complete overhaul of the visual look and feel of the site, improve checkout process to increase conversion rate, and improve sign-in/sign-out process to increase repeat business with faster task completion of repeat orders.

# **Senior Interaction Designer**

June 2009 - May 2016, Florida International University, Miami, FL USA

#### Notable Highlights:

Redesigned FIU's campus maps in two weeks by focusing & designing on a minimum viable product (MVP) using a lean UX design process. The new design resulted in a 191% increase (9,000 new people) in mobile users, and a 146% increase (938 new people) in tablet users.

Created a usability lab to increase awareness on web accessibility and UI design for the university which will save the university over \$12,000 on usability testing every year.

Presented a responsive design strategy to increase FIU.edu's digital footprint in mobile, tablet, and desktop platforms. This strategy resulted in a 162% increase in new mobile users (151,000 new people), and a 151% increase in new tablet users (75,700 new people) for fiu.edu from 2012 to 2013.

Led over 30 website redesigns throughout my tenure including two fiu.edu website redesigns.

# Web Designer

November 2007 - June 2009, University of Miami - College of Business, Miami, FL USA

#### Notable Highlights:

Managed UM's School of Business website while ensuring effective creative content development and execution to support program and media efforts to over 60,000 visitors a month.

#### **Software Security Engineer**

January 2006 - April 2006, Department of Defense, TS/SI, Seasonal Internship Program Information Assurance – Spring 2006

#### Notable Highlights:

Assisted to develop a set of prototype plug-ins using Eclipse Integrated Development Environment (IDE) to evaluate the security strength of source code design. Familiar with Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS 140) and Common Criteria security practices.

#### Portfolio & Case Studies

http://fabuloso.me http://behance.net/fabuloso

## **SKILLS**

User Research HTML & CSS Competitive Analysis Sass & Compass **Usability Testing** i0uerv **Content Inventory** Xcode & Swift **Analytics** Lean UX Use Cases Site Maps Visual Design Wireframes **Brand Identity** Prototyping Team Leadership

## **EDUCATION**

MFA, Graphic Design, 2018 University of Miami

MS, Telecom & Networking, 2006 Florida International University

BS, Computer Science, 2003 Florida International University

## **RECENT AWARDS**

FIU Employee Recognition Nominee 2011, 2013

Council for Advancement and Support for Education Award Nominee (For distinguished work in higher ed) 2013, 2014

FIU Service Excellence Award 2016

## **TOOLS**

Adobe Creative Suite Sketchbooks
Sublime Text Timeboxing
OmniFocus OmniGraffle
Foundation Silverback
Sketch Git
Framer InVision

### **HOBBIES**

Photography Sports
Lettering Video Games
DJ Culinary Arts

